Inventory of the Papers of Richard B. Lillich, 1927 [1957-1996]-1996
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
- Iran-U.S. Claims Tribunal
  - Memorial of Islamic Republic of Iran in Response to the Reply Memorial of the United States 1988 (Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous: "Expulsion in International Law. A Study in International Aliens Law and Human Rights with Special Reference to Finland" 1987 (Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous: "Iranian-Forum Clauses and the Jurisdiction of the US-Iranian Claims Settlement Tribunal" 1985 (Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous Papers 1981-1985, 6 folders (Box 53)
  - Mitigation of Damages Memo and Related Papers 1982 (Box 54)
  - Morrison-Knudsen International, Inc. v. National Iranian Oil Co. 1984-1985, 4 folders (Box 54)
  - Reza Nemazee and Luz Belen Nemazee v. Iran 1982 (Box 55)
  - Otis Elevator Co. v. Iran and Bank Mellot (Case No. 284) 1987 (Box 55)
  - Opinion of Law. Basic Approaches Concerning the Binding Effect of Forum Clauses 1986 (Box 55)
  - Thomas Earl Payne v. Iran 1984-1985, 4 folders (Box 56)
  - Persinger v. US and Iran 1981 (Box 56)
  - Rankin v. Iran; US v. Iran (Claim No. 10913) 1984-1986, 3 folders (Box 56)
  - Saghi v. Iran 1991, 2 folders (Box 57)
  - Sedco, Inc. v. National Iranian Oil Co. and Iran 1985-1986 (Box 58)
  - Sherman, Milton; Phoenix Canada Oil Co. Ltd. v. Texaco, Inc. et al 1985 (Box 58)
  - Short, Alfred L. W. v. Iran (Claim No. 11135) 1985 (Box 58)
  - Small Iranian Claims 1981 (Box 58)
  - Sperry Corp. v. Iran 1981 (Box 58)
  - Standing to Sue 1982 (Box 58)
  - Stewart, David P. Correspondence 1983-1986 (Box 58)
  - Stockholders Claims 1982-1983 (Box 59)
  - Torfin v. Iran; US v. Iran (Case No. 10729) 1986 (Box 59)
  - Ultrasystems, Inc. v. Iran 1975 (Box 59)
  - US v. Iran (Case B/36) 1988, 5 folders (Box 59)
  - US v. Iran (Case No. 10729) 1986, 2 folders (Box 60)
  - US v. Iran (Case No. 10913) 1986 (Box 61)
  - US v. Iran Memorial of the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran 1988 (Box 61)
  - Walters, Lee E. v. Iran 1987 (Box 61)
  - Yeager, Kenneth P. v. Iran (Claim No. 10199) 1987 (Box 2 folders)
- Sokol Colloquium
  - Sokol Colloquium Series 1991-1993 (Box 62)
  - Sokol Correspondence with Sokol Family 1982 (Box 62)
  - Sokol I: Enforcement of Foreign Judgements and Arbitral Awards 1977-1978 (Box 62)
  - Sokol II: Providing Foreign and International Law in Domestic Tribunals 1978 (Box 62)
  - Sokol III: The Family in International Law 1979 (Box 62)
  - Sokol III: Reading Materials 1979 (Box 62)
  - Sokol IV: International Aspects of Criminal Law 1979-1980 (Box 62)
  - Sokol V: The Harmonization of Laws Within the European Economic Community 1980-1981 (Box 62)
  - Sokol VI: Resolving Transnational Disputes Through International Arbitration 1982 (Box 63)
  - Sokol VII: The Iran-US Arbitral Tribunal 1983, 2 folders (Box 63)
  - Sokol VIII: International Debt Restructuring 1984 (Box 63)
  - Sokol X: List of Participants. Miscellaneous Correspondence, Papers 1988, 4 folders (Box 64)
  - Sokol X: Five videotapes of the panels 1988 (Box 64)
- Published Articles
  - State of New York. Municipal Officials and Conflicts of Interest. An Analysis of the State of the Law and a Proposed Status. Prepared by Milton Kaplan and Richard Lillich, December 1, 1957 (Box 65)
  - A Case Study in Consular and Diplomatic Immunity, Syracuse L. Rev. (1961) (Box 65)
  - Judicial Review and the FCSC, Admn. L. Rev. (1963) (Box 65)
  - The United States-Bulgarian Claims Agreement of 1963, Am. J. Int'l L. (1964) (Box 65)
  - SW Africa: The UN's Takeover BID, New Society, 10 November 1966 (Box 65)
  - Uthant and Vietnam, New Society, 13 April 1967 (Box 65)
  - The U.N. and the Middle East, New Society, 1 June 1967 (Box 65)
  - World Report. The Republican Choice, New Society, 14 September 1967 (Box 65)
  - Miscellaneous articles related to the papers (Box 65)
  - Personal Agendas 1970-1973, 1980-1993 (Box 65)
- Organ Transplation, Lump Sum and Miscellaneous Files
  - Canada's Human Tissue Acts 1973-1976 (Box 66)
  - Council of Europe: International Exchange and Transportation of Human Substances 1979-1986 (Box 66)
  - ONU Reports on Slavery and Slavery-Like Practices. Organ Transplantation 1989-1996 (Box 66)
  - Organ Transplantation International Laws: United Kingdom, Turkey, Switzerland, Spain, Portugal, Norway, Luxemborg, Italy, Greece, France, Denmark, Cyprus n.d., 2 folders (Box 66)
  - Organ Transplantation Miscellaneous Articles and Reports 1986-1996, 2 folders (Box 66)
  - Organ Transplantation Miscellaneous Correspondence 1989-1993 (Box 67)
  - Organ Transplant Proposal 1984-1996 (Box 67)
  - Organ Transplantation Issues and Recommendations. Report of the Task Force 1986 (Box 67)
  - Lump Sum Correspondence 1969-1971 (Box 68)
  - Lump Sum Correspondence 1982-1984, 2 folders (Box 68)
  - Lump Sum Correspondence-Summer 1969 (Box 68)
  - Lump Sum Correspondence with Foreign Embassies A-Z 1968-1971 (Box 69)
  - Lump Sum Correspondence. Lillich-India 1976 (Box 69)
  - Lump Sum Correspondence-Sri Lanka 1982 (Box 69)
  - Lump Sum Junk Agreements 1950s-1960s, 3 folders (Box 69)
  - Iraqi Claims 1990-1991, 2 folders (Box 70)
  - South Africa Sanctions 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box 70)
  - Vols. 1-4 of "Termo de Abertura" (ledgers) for the Mobil Oil Southern African Tty? Ltd [Portuguese] 1966-1973 (Box 71-72)
  - 3 boxes of card files (Box 73)
- Photographs
  - U.S. Naval War College. International Law Study 1966-1971
  - Lillich, Richard B. [Portrait] 1971, 1994, Photograph Collection
  - Law School Faculty 1977-1978, Photograph Collection
  - Sokol Colloquium IV 1980, Photograph Collection
  - Lillich [with Human Rights activists?] 1981, 1991, Photograph Collection